commerzbank.com 2012-10-09

# Privacy

Commerzbank AG takes the protection of your personal data very seriously and strictly observes data protection rules. Personal data are collected on this website only to the extent that is technically necessary. Under no circumstances will we pass the data collected on to third parties without the consent of those concerned. The following declaration provides an overview of how Commerzbank AG ensures this protection, what type of data are collected, and for what purpose.

  * **Data processing on this internet site**

Commerzbank AG collects and automatically saves in its server log files some of the information normally transmitted by the browser, provided that your browser makes such information available. Such data cannot be assigned by Commerzbank AG to specific individuals. The data are not pooled with other data sources.

  * **Cookies**

Occasionally, visits to our internet site will lead to cookies being copied onto your computer, i.e. small text files which are stored by your browser. They help to make the service we provide more user-friendly, effective and safe. Passwords are not copied into cookies. Most of the cookies we use are so-called session cookies and are automatically reset when you go offline. If you end the session by closing your browser, the cookie will be preserved for a while and will then either be overwritten or deleted by the client. Our cookies will not do any damage to your computer and contain no viruses.

  * **Webtracking**

On this website data are collected and stored through web-controlling technologies in an anonymous form and solely for the purpose of optimization measures. User profiles are created under a pseudonym from this data. Cookies may also be used for this purpose which collect and store data solely in a pseudonym form. The data are not utilised to personally identify the visitor of this website and will not be collated with data via the bearer of the pseudonym. No personal data are stored. Further to the law this also includes the so called IP-address of the user. The IP-address will be made unrecognizable and will not enable any inferences to be made about the visitor of the web site. This procedure was approved by the data protection officer of Hamburg further to §38 section 1 of the Federal Data Protection Law.  

**
  * Collecting, processing and use of your personal data
**

We will ask you to provide your name, address and e-mail address in an order form, so that we can send you the publications or newsletters offered on our website, or which you have ordered, These data will be stored and used exclusively for mailing purposes. They will not be passed on to third parties. By entering your data (name, address, e-mail details) into the template, you will give us your consent to store the data and use them so that we can provide the information requested. The personal data which you supply to subscribe to the newsletter will be stored until you cancel your subscription.

**
  * Right to obtain information
**

You have the right to be informed on the personal data stored, on the receiver of such data, and the purpose of processing your data at any time. The data protection controller of Commerzbank AG will provide you with information on the data stored.

**
  * Further information
**

We greatly appreciate your confidence in us. Therefore we wish to be available at all times to answer questions on the processing and use of your personal data. If you wish to receive information not offered by this declaration, or if you wish to receive more detailed information on a subject, please get in touch with Commerzbank AG’s data protection controller at any time.
